Lilian Okeke

🜙+2348100181416 🔀 Lilianokeke.ca@gmail.com 🛅 <u>linkedin.com/in/lilianada</u> 🐧 <u>github.com/lilianada</u> 🚳 <u>Liliydesigned.me</u>

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

Graduate Diploma in Software Engineering

Alt School Africa

Bachelor of Education (Honours)

Nnamdi Azikiwe University, Anambra, Nigeria - CGPA 3.6 of 5.0

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

She Code Africa Community

February 2024 - Present

Frontend Technical Channel Coordinator (Volunteer)

- Recently appointed to oversee and manage the frontend technical channel engagements, activities, and program planning for She Code Africa.
- Initiating strategies for enhancing community interaction and member participation, with a focus on fostering an inclusive and respectful environment.
- Tasked with the coordination, and support of channel members, ensuring the smooth running of community events.

Supreme Marketing Limited, Malta

July 2022 - March 2024

Lead Frontend Engineer (Full-time)

- Leading an Agile team of front-end developers in building and maintaining fintech apps for clients in Europe.
- Optimizing websites and web applications performance to enhance user experience and overall growth of client's product.
- Ensured cross-browser compatibility and followed SEO best practices for all websites.
- Learnt flutter on the job and completed two mobile app projects that are production-ready.

Funconnect, Nigeria Jan 2023 - May 2023

Frontend Developer (Contract)

- Led the development and testing of over 10 dynamic user interfaces for Fun Connect's Landing Pages, Admin Dashboard, and user dashboard, employing React JS and modern web technologies. Successfully integrated responsive design principles to ensure seamless user experiences across various devices.
- Spearheaded performance optimization initiatives for Fun Connect's web applications, achieving a 30% reduction in load times through efficient code refactoring and leveraging advanced web performance techniques.
- Worked closely with backend developers, designers, and product managers to align web functionalities with organizational goals, resulting in a more cohesive and user-centric product.

March 2022 - Dec 2022 **Coloring Cultures USA**

Product Manager and Frontend Developer (Contract)

- Successfully recruited and onboarded a skilled team of 3 mobile developers, 2 web developers, and 1 backend developer with a quality assurance tester and UI/UX designer within a challenging timeframe of 2 weeks.
- Directed the end-to-end development of the mobile and web application, leading a cross-functional team of 6 developers, designer, and QA specialist.
- Managed and coordinated the development process, ensuring timely delivery and adherence to the client's specifications, timeframe and budget.
- Contributed to the building of the app's web dashboard and as well as the start and completion of the landing page of the app as a whole.

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

As a front-end developer, I specialize in creating immersive user experiences with technologies like React.js, Next Js, and Typescript. With three years of experience, I've delivered products to clients globally, from startups to corporations, and individuals. Eager to adapt to new technologies, I strive to create digital products that are intuitive and visually captivating. My goal when joining any organization is to learn, grow, collaborate and enjoy the process of building or improving a product that clients and users will enjoy.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Javascript, React.js, Next Js, Typescript, Redux, Context API, Html / Css, Git / GitHub, Npm / Yarn, Netlify / Vercel, Tailwind

KEY COMPETENCIES

User-centered design, Attention to detail, Team collaboration, Critical thinking skills, Adaptability and continuous learning, Project management, Leadership and team management, Community management and engagement.